I've experienced death so many times.
But never my own.
Talk to me.
We have penetrating thoracic trauma
by gunshot, catastrophic blood loss.
We're losing him. Defib on my count.
Three. Two. One. Clear.
No pulse. Recharging.
We have a heartbeat.
A beating heart. I'll take it.
It really is like they say,
your life flashes before your eyes.
My god. My god.
All right, we're at
ten centimeters dilated. It's crowning.
Keep pushing.
That's it.
Keep pushing. You're doing great.
Big push. One last one.
Time of birth, 2300 hours, 21 minutes.
February 1, 1971.
Congratulations. It's a boy.
And in the beginning... There was blood.
What're you gonna name
your son, miss moser?
Dexter.
His name is Dexter.
Yeah.
Trying to cop a feel, freak?
I'm experiencing death.
You only get one first time.
Dude, what fucking planet you from?
That's enough.
Let Dexter focus.
Problem?
Yeah, no blood.
No problem.
Heartless. Like the tin man.
And maybe... like me.
Impeccable work as always, Dexter.
You're gonna make an
excellent surgeon one day.
I've been preparing for today
for such a long time, but
I didn't feel... anything.
That's what makes you special.
That's what makes me me.
It's traditional to smile.
I wasn't smiling?
Just think of something
that makes you happy.
Motherfucker.
Goddamn it.
Sergeant Morgan.
Captain Spencer.
What the fuck? And who the fuck?
We're asking the same questions.
Right now, it's all preliminary.
- Well, I am all ears.
- Stop.
Until forensics is done with our sweep,
you are all guests at my crime scene.
Even you, captain. Bootie up.
Yes, ma'am.
All right. What do you got?
Looks like the intruder used
a box cutter to gain entry
through the back screen porch.
Yeah, he shot the parents, point blank,
and the little girl in the
back as she ran for the stairs.
Then pilfered everything in sight.
Cash, jewelry, cards.
You said "intruder," as in
there was only one perp?
Based on the muddy
footprints all over the place,
only one. Experienced, prepared.
Wore booties over shoes.
Ergo, no tread marks to trace.
You're giving me a
whole lot of nothing here.
A family is dead. What do we have?
Hey, officer Sanders, was the
TV on when you arrived here?
Negative, sergeant.
All right, so this poor family,
they're chowing down,
watching television...
The intruder turns it off.
I'm seeing blood on the "on/off" switch.
Masuka, when you're done
with the other 700 things going on here,
would you run this for prints?
It'll be number 701, sergeant.
Could've at least killed
the fucking cow first.
And you could at least not
curse at the dinner table.
Sorry. It's just how it comes out.
So, graduation's in a week.
Anything fun happening?
I heard about some party
at delta Alpha something.
But I'm not going.
I'll represent. Show the world
there's at least one Morgan with a life.
You're going to a college party?
Dad, come on. We both
know that you're gonna say no,
I'm gonna go anyway, and
the world isn't gonna end,
so why don't we just
skip the drama for once?
- I'm okay with you going.
- Seriously?
One condition. You take your brother.
- What?
You need to get out more,
spend time with people your own age.
Be a part of something.
Yes, he should do that,
but far away from me.
- It's my one condition.
- Unbelievable.
- Hey.
- Fuck me.
So how'd it go yesterday?
Dr. Rivas said I did a good job.
Well, that's great, right?
I guess.
But...
It didn't give me the
feeling I thought it would.
I know we hoped slicing
into bodies would be enough.
But i-I'm still
hungry.
Just stick with the plan.
Four years of med
school, then a residency.
We have plenty of
time to figure all this out.
No, I don't know. I-I'm worried the plan
isn't going to satisfy my... urges.
It has to.
You guys have a good day.
All those shiny, happy people.
So excited to plan their lives.
And all I wanted to do was end one.
Are those real dead bodies?
Kind of cool, right?
Name's masuka, look me up if
you ever get a speeding ticket.
Nice booth.
My father actually
works for Miami Metro.
Harry Morgan. You know him?
Come on, baby, come to daddy.
Want to see my nine-inch nail?
Really? Poser.
Hey, are number seven and
number 12 the same killer?
What? No.
Can you move? You're
cock blocking my booth.
Shoo.
This is starting to look like
a serial killer art project up in here.
And we are the parents
displaying it on our fucking fridge!
I'm not a proud mama, fellas.
I am one pissed-off, menopausal bitch.
We have three home
invasion sites in three counties.
Eight dead, including two children.
I will not and I cannot wait
for the next one to happen.
Do you understand me?
- Yes, captain.
- I got something.
- Thank fucking god.
Okay, that partial we
took off that VCR remote
gave us four hits.
This guy's in prison.
Deceased.
Five-foot-four.
And then there's him. Levi Reed.
Extensive b&e jacket.
Plus, he's six-three, which matches
the muddy footprints
we found on the scene.
The only way we're gonna
stop this is if we bust his ass.
Alert SWAT. We are doing this now.
Hey. See if the door's open first.
- Clear.
Downstairs is clear.
Got him!
Yo. Shoes.
You killed two kids. Fuck you.
Fuck your shoes.
Get him out of my face.
Come on. This way.
Before I actually did the deed,
I spent a lot of time fantasizing about it.
Dreaming about a world of possibilities.
But at the tender age
of 20, I was still a virgin.
Ted Bundy.
The most charming man in the world.
And one of the most
prolific serial killers ever.
Adept at blending in, until he wasn't.
I wondered if I was like him.
Or the night stalker.
Or btk.
Or even the zodiac killer.
I even wondered if I'd end
up with a nickname, too.
Time to go.
It's not what you think.
How about you shove
that nudie magazine
underneath your pillow
and join me in the real world
where real women with
real tits actually exist?
If you and dad say so.
Who knows? You might even
meet someone and have fun.
I have fun.
Choking your chicken doesn't count.
Come on. You're driving, I'm drinking.
My god!
- Sophia.
- Deb.
Why is your brother here?
Our father made her bring me.
Okay... So, what do I do?
Disappear for two hours.
Don't talk to me until I need a ride home.
Debra Morgan. Badass.
I'm just getting started. Where's the keg?
Keg? We can do better.
Tequila. Seltzer.
And slam.
Is that all you got?
Harry wanted me to get out,
to be with people my own age.
Be a part of something.
Was this really what he meant?
It all seemed so
unsanitary.
Hey, handsome.
Extremely unsanitary.
- Gay? Not interested? What?
- Girlfriend.
Do you have any x?
I tried to stop them,
but the door's locked.
- Who?
- Deb and Andy.
Sh-sh-she was drinking, like a lot,
like, like blacked out,
- and he took her upstairs.
- Which room?
Second floor, first on the left.
Hey! Watch it, bro.
Kind of busy in here.
- Deb!
- Dude! Get the fuck out of here!
What's your deal, asshole?
Go home, you fucking psycho.
Take your slut sister with you.
The fuck was that, Dex?
I was just trying to protect you.
By publicly humiliating me?
You were unconscious in his room.
I had too much to drink.
He said that I could lie down in there.
When I got there, the door was locked
and his pants were off.
Did he...?
- No.
- Deb!
I was so scared. Are you okay?
I will be.
Dex got there before anything happened.
I used to make fun of you
for watching wrestlemania all the time,
but that in there, that was... wow.
Shit.
It's already past curfew.
Go. I got it.
You're a lifesaver, again.
Deb, I'll call you tomorrow?
Hold my fucking hair back.
Hey. Tylenol, water, bed.
And quietly.
I know.
Way past curfew, kids.
How was the party?
- It was...
- you were right.
Yeah, I'm glad I went.
Made lots of friends.
Go to bed.
Sorry to keep you up, dad.
I know we're supposed to
go hunting in a few hours.
I can't sleep unless I know my
kids are home safe and sound.
Get some rest.
Well, this game has certainly
- lived up to the hype.
- Come on, come on.
- Come on, come on...
- Dolphins and cowboys.
Griese to throw.
Incomplete.
Come on! He was wide open.
Seven-seven with 5:21
to play in the fourth.
Deep down the sidelines,
caught by Fleming at the seven
and thrown out of bounds by Harris.
A gain of 35 yards.
That's the big play Miami has
been looking for all afternoon.
First and goal with 4:48 remaining.
And of course, for
griese and the dolphins,
this is more than just a game.
Hey, bud, where are you?
Dolphins are about to score.
But make no mistake.
- Hey, junior.
- They are still haunted
- by losing to Dallas...
- Jun
two years ago in...
First and goal from the seven.
Jesus!
Fuck!
Help!
Somebody! Help!
Dear god.
- Now, Doris. Doris.
- What happened?!
Doris, Doris, Doris.
I'm sorry, it was an accident, I... My baby.
I'm sorry.
Why?!
For most fathers and sons,
a hunting trip is about bonding
about teaching your son the skills
to survive on his own.
For us, it was that. And more.
Harry knew I had specific needs.
And we tried everything
we could to control them.
- Dad?
- I'm fine.
What'd you get? All right.
These look fresh.
It's been a while since
you bagged a boar.
Tracks look deep. Must be a big one.
So, what do you think?
Pork chops tonight or sliders?
- Dex?
- Dad...
These hunting trips don't
work for me anymore.
What do you mean?
Animals aren't enough.
These... feelings I have.
- I can't ignore them.
- No, no.
It's too soon.
You taught me the code
to help me channel my urges.
What's the point if I can't even use it?
Killing a person... It's not that simple.
Once you do it, it can't be undone.
I almost did.
- What?
- Kill someone.
Last night at the party.
What happened?
I promised Deb I wouldn't
- say anything.
- Come on, please.
I know she was drinking.
There was this guy.
He was trying to take advantage of her.
And?
I threw him down the stairs.
He hit me. I hit him back, but
then I saw his blood.
And everything became really clear.
There was a knife on the bar.
More than anything in my whole life,
I wanted to take that knife.
What stopped you?
Deb.
She yanked me off of him.
If it hadn't been for her, I...
Dad?
Dad!
God!
Help!
We need help here. Help!
- What's his name?
- Harry.
Any history of heart attacks?
- Prior surgery?
- No.
Dad? Dad?
I'm gonna be okay. I'm gonna be okay.
Hang back here, hon.
Give us room to work.
I promise, we'll take good care of him.
For the first time, the
idea of death became...
Excruciating.
How can you fucking
eat at a time like this?
I could always eat at a time like this.
But...
You okay?
Of course I'm not fucking okay.
What if he doesn't make it, Dex?
I didn't get to see him this morning.
You guys left so early.
I never got a chance to say goodbye.
To tell him I love him.
I was there.
And I didn't do that.
Dad knows you love him, Deb.
That's not the point, Dex. God, you...
Here you are, dear.
Any update?
I'm sorry to say your father
suffered a heart attack.
My god.
But he's currently
stable and in great hands.
Okay, sweetheart?
You all can see him and the doctor now.
Your father's blood work indicates
he suffered a non-st-elevation
myocardial infarction.
Fuck does that mean?
Deb, language, come on.
It means I got a little blockage.
Nothing serious.
A few pills, I'm out of the woods, right?
Not quite. We're gonna need
to hold you for further testing.
All goes well, you could be
home by the end of the week.
But you're gonna need
to stick to a strict diet.
And quit fucking smoking.
Excuse my French.
Your French is excellent.
You're gonna want to manage stress,
of course, it's very important.
Unfortunately, I was the stress.
Hey, don't you have some,
like, big game coming up?
Regionals.
Don't know if I'm going.
Dad would want you to play.
Dad's not here.
Well, I am. I'll go to your game.
Just save me an aisle seat.
Wait, you actually want to
come to my volleyball game?
We're supposed to
support each other, right?
As a family?
What family?
Soon we won't even
need a fucking table.
Just two TV trays.
The doctor said he might
be out by the end of the week.
And then what? He's gonna
go right back to drinking
and smoking and all his
other self-destructive shit.
Look at all this crap.
No wonder his heart tried to peace out.
- Fuck.
- Deb... Stop.
It's gonna be okay.
That's what everyone
said before mom died.
Fuck!
Dex.
We should probably wipe
the floor before that dries.
Some fucking support, Dex.
The next few days
of Harry's hospitalization were... Odd.
His condition didn't improve.
It was in those days that I realized
that grief is like an ocean.
Sometimes it's calm.
Other times the waves
can overwhelm you.
Times like that, people
say the best you can do
is just learn to swim.
But I planned to do so
much more than just swim.
And that was when I
realized that nurse Mary
just might be a fellow traveler.
And how are we doing
this sunshiny day?
Why is my father getting worse?
Dear.
It's never easy seeing
a loved one in pain.
What is that you just gave him?
It's complicated.
Try me.
I'm pre-med.
Your father made a lifetime
of bad choices for his health.
This... this is the result.
So all we can do is give him
the medicine that he needs
to come out on the other side.
Don't worry. This too shall pass.
It was then I decided
it wasn't Harry who was going to pass.
Hello, dear. Can I help with anything?
I'm just kind of... lost.
Cute cat.
That's Mr. Tinker. Such a love.
I'd always had a kinship with cats.
Nature's own serial killers.
I've got to head down the hall.
If you need anything, just ask.
Her trophies.
Every picture tells a story.
Can I help you, Dexter?
I need to use the ion
mobility spectrometer.
I-It's for a finals project.
Help yourself. But I got a
class coming in 40 minutes.
High potassium nitrate levels.
I noticed that.
What would happen if this solution
were delivered to
someone intravenously?
At this dilution? Harmless.
But if administered repeatedly
over the course of several days
it could kill someone.
Thanks, Dr. Rivas.
Hey, how detectable
would that be in, say,
a forensics medical examination?
Nearly undetectable.
The body does a great
job of processing high levels
of potassium nitrate,
even while it kills you.
I had been hanging around
a real-deal serial killer all this time.
I was hoping I'd get to practice
my own brand of bedside manner.
There she was,
in the halls of healing,
only death on her mind.
If I asked Harry to let her be my first kill,
he would have said no.
He was too protective... Of me.
The kill had to be his idea.
Poor dear.
I think that the shots she's giving
are killing you. You're only getting worse.
Don't... let her.
All right, my brave little soldier.
Let's get this out of the way.
Wait.
Harry doesn't want the shot.
Harry's in a lot of pain.
I want the pain.
He wants the pain.
It was at that moment she revealed
she also had a dark passenger.
More important.
Harry saw it, too.
Doctor's not gonna be happy
that you're refusing your meds.
You can tell.
She's killing you
with high levels of potassium nitrate.
Stop
her.
I'd been waiting to hear
those words for so long.
Harry's been training me
for this moment for years.
Whoa.
Hey, I was new at this.
But tonight... Tonight's the night.
I hate that I'm missing the game tonight.
Don't worry. Dex is taking your place.
No offense, dad, but you look like shit.
Go. Win it for me.
I'll be at the next one.
You never forget your first time.
Mine was with an older woman.
Mr. Tinker, where are you, kitty?
Ladies and gentlemen,
give it up for your manatees!
Debra Morgan!
I've been looking
through your photo album.
So many wonderful memories.
I hope you don't mind.
Are all your victims in here?
Let me help you with that.
Scream again and lose a tongue.
I helped them.
I took their pain away.
- They didn't ask you to do that.
- They didn't have to.
These goddamn people
drinking and smoking
till their hearts give out.
Slaves to their own compulsions.
Just look at your father.
I already lost my
mother. Harry's all I've got,
and you tried to take him away from me.
That was the first time I ever felt
someone else's fear.
And I liked it.
Got it!
And it's Morgan for the kill!
And the manatees win!
I really hate mosquitos.
My first trophies.
I didn't know it then,
but it would end up
being a terrible mistake.
I stuck to dad's code.
The rules were there for a reason.
To protect us.
To keep the innocent safe.
And, most importantly
for me, to never get...
Caught.
Who are you?
I live here.
- Hey, Dexter.
- Bobby.
Good to see you, kid. This is Harry's boy.
Dexter, it's so good to see you.
We're all pulling for your pop.
If there's anything you, your sister need,
just let me know, I'll
make it happen, okay?
Thanks.
How's that goddaughter of
mine handling everything?
You know.
Deb is... Deb.
- Yeah.
- What's all this?
Last thing you should be worrying about
is filling the fridge.
Yeah, and you know, I got
I told them half pepperoni.
You know, heart healthy.
Well, that's such a... Relief.
Nice gesture.
You can leave it all on the kitchen table.
There he is. D-man. D-Dawg.
Remember me from the job fair?
Was hoping we'd catch you here.
You, caught me.
I brought you kids
some hamburger helper.
My kids live off this stuff.
Dexter, meet Tanya Martin.
Aka "the boss lady of forensics."
I've heard a lot about you.
Really?
I've worked with Harry for years.
He's a great cop. Bet
he's taught you well.
She had no idea.
Dude, you had such great instincts
with those photos at the job fair.
Linking them to the same killer?
That's exactly what we thought.
Wow. Cool.
Turned out not to be true, though.
But it took us six weeks
to recognize the similarities.
You picked them out in six seconds.
I made a few calls.
Your professor, Dr. Rivas, told me
you're the most talented
student he's ever had.
Well, I don't know what to say.
Say yes, 'cause you've earned
yourself a job offer, d-money.
A paid internship.
$4.25 an hour.
Think about it.
It was perfect timing.
I was starving after... well...
- Hey.
Where were you all night?
Like you care.
I was at Sofia's.
Her parents took us out
to celebrate after the big game.
You know, the one that we won?
You know, the one that
you said you'd come to
but then blew off.
Deb... I didn't think
you'd really come anyway.
I'm sorry.
What's all this?
Dad's work friends dropped it off.
Well, wasn't that real
fucking thoughtful of them?
Congratulations, class of 1991.
I didn't blame Deb for
missing my graduation.
After all, I hadn't come through for her.
I was alone, and somehow
that seemed appropriate.
I thought you were mad at
me for missing your game.
I'm still royally pissed, but like you said
we're family.
I am gonna ream you
out tomorrow, though.
I mean, what a dick move.
So, it was always about family.
What a concept.
You did it.
Sorry, I couldn't find your
nurse for the life of me.
What were you two talking about?
About going home.
Okay.
It's too bad you had
to miss graduation, dad.
You should've seen
what a dope Dex was.
He just sat there with
his cap on like an idiot.
Everyone had already thrown theirs off.
Isn't that right, Dex?
I wish I could've seen it.
Well, your presence was felt.
I can't believe how much better you look.
It's almost a miracle.
Man.
Coming through.
I love it!
All right.
Whoo!
Anything I can get you?
No.
Okay. Well, if you need
anything in the night...
The nurse.
No witnesses?
None.
And, most importantly,
she'll never hurt anyone again.
What did you do with the body?
She'll... Never be found.
What did you do with it?
I wrapped her up,
stuck her in the back of the pickup
and drove out to interstate 75.
Alligator alley.
I dropped her in a
batch of hungry gators.
She was gone in seconds.
Dad, there's literally
nothing to worry about
because there's literally
nothing left of her.
How did it feel?
It felt
right.
Good night, son.
I'll see you in the morning.
Good night, dad.
Change was never easy for Harry.
I don't approve of you doing this, Dex.
But I was at a point in my life
where change was necessary.
You're always telling me
to be part of something.
It was... good.
This is me following my father's advice.
- Sarge.
- Angel.
Thank god.
Welcome back.
- Bobby.
- I knew you'd get through, pal.
Good to see you.
It's great to see you, sir.
Clark, good to see you, too.
Harry.
Camilla. Missed you.
Dexter, Doris would be so proud.
Hey, the place felt empty without you.
- Hey.
- Welcome back.
Missed you, too.
Another Morgan in the building.
Hopefully, you're not
a chip off the old block.
Nice haircut.
My father was a man
with so many friends.
And I, well, I... wasn't.
You're late, newbie.
- I am?
- I'm just shitting you.
Tanya.
Dexter.
Welcome to the first
day of the rest of your life.
I hope you'll be happy here.
I'm sure I will be.
I know you think you know it all,
but you've got a lot to learn, amigo.
Take a seat.
You get the little one.
My new life.
Thought it might be a good
idea to take it for a spin.